[{"id": "5a162d06f01ec323f8491735", "question": "What do O.J Simpson's initials stand for?", "answer": "Orenthal James", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea4028ff048f679a45ab65", "question": "An infectious particle that can only reproduce inside a living cell is called what?", "answer": "Virus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b21e", "question": "What city was Indira Gandhi killed in?", "answer": "New Delhi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a08b", "question": "Which two teams automatically qualified for the 1998 soccer World Cup?", "answer": "France and Brazil", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdd59e20499cffc60b8422b", "question": "What was the last Province to join Canada?", "answer": "Newfoundland and Labrador", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390a2", "question": "In Greek mythology, who are Demeter's siblings?", "answer": "Poseidon, Zeus, Hades, Hera, Hestia, Chiron", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399a1", "question": "What 1997 film featured Clint Eastwood, Gene Hackman, Ed Harris, and E.G. Marshall?", "answer": "Absolute Power", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b152", "question": "In what year did Atlanta become the fifth capital of Georgia?", "answer": "1868", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a8e", "question": "Who created the character Conan the Barbarian?", "answer": "Robert E. Howard", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8f4", "question": "What do you have if you are suffering from circadian dysrhythmia?", "answer": "Jet lag", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339229", "question": "Who is pictured with her eyes wide open on posters for Kubrick's \"Eyes Wide Shut\" movie?", "answer": "Nicole Kidman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393d6", "question": "Who danced alongside Shirley Temple in the motion picture \"Captain January\"?", "answer": "Buddy Ebsen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937e9a508d98002fdd6339b", "question": "Who is Donald Duck's girlfriend?", "answer": "Daisy Duck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe76685eec85e375820b282", "question": "What is the Japanese word for \"dog\"?", "answer": "Inu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b9a", "question": "What actress replaced Shannen Doherty on the TV show \"Charmed\"?", "answer": "Rose McGowan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9d7", "question": "What color is malachite?", "answer": "Green", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600241284be4723ccac22171", "question": "\"Peter and the Wolf\" is a musical composition written by which Russian composer?", "answer": "Sergei Prokofiev", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e6bcfe83fe1f2a824bd1", "question": "Who gave Queen Elizabeth I the soubriquet \"Gloriana\"?", "answer": "Edmund Spenser, in his epic poem \"The Faerie Queene\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "596dffd39616e6c6d4eba500", "question": "The Spanish Civil War began in what year? ", "answer": "1936", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3b7", "question": "What are categorized as the biological class \"aves\"?", "answer": "Birds", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a3", "question": "What color is Shrek?", "answer": "Green", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015fad3fe83fe1f2a824c36", "question": "What was the profession of St. Patrick's father?", "answer": "St. Patrick's father was a deacon while his grandfather was a Christian priest.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e6b", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"Scent of a Woman\"?", "answer": "Al Pacino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c3049076251badbeacf", "question": "Which unique pet did Calvin Coolidge have during his presidency?", "answer": "Raccoon -- Named Rachel, she might be the most well known pet.  She walked around on a leash and was the master of mischief.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397b1", "question": "What sitcom star did Mt. Airy, North Carolina rename a stretch of Highway 52 after, in 2002?", "answer": "Andy Griffith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b371951c3f17ccc40c8e1f", "question": "Which Irish poet said \"There are no strangers here; Only friends you have not yet met.\"?", "answer": "William Butler Yeats", "category": "art"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396aa", "question": "What brand of beverage has its containers visible in many shots in the movie \"Fight Club\"?", "answer": "Starbucks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cd536e347d002c297e4b6", "question": "Which book did James Fenimore Cooper publish in 1826 that was later made into a movie, starring Daniel Day-Lewis?", "answer": "The Last of the Mohicans", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76f0aeec85e375820b2e2", "question": "Which country has the longest town name?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133943e", "question": "What does Morpheus tell Neo to follow in \"The Matrix\"?", "answer": "The White Rabbit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388c8", "question": "Who created the character Hercule Poirot?", "answer": "Agatha Christie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8af", "question": "In what city would you find Centennial Olympic Park?", "answer": "Atlanta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58bb34e9e368446ca7bd684c", "question": "What widely consumed drug acts as a natural defence to protect the seeds of the coffee plant?", "answer": "Caffeine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c259", "question": "What is another name for tetanus?", "answer": "Lockjaw", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffe4bd247818f5674af01b4", "question": "What is the name of the book the movie \"Goodfellas\" is based on?", "answer": "\"Wiseguy: Life in a Mafia Family\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cd85ee347d002c297e4c7", "question": "Who flew too close to the Sun??", "answer": "Icarus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4d9", "question": "What fruit comes in Bing and Rainier variety?", "answer": "Cherries", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392e8", "question": "In the movie \"The Terminator\", what did the cyborg remove in order to repair itself?", "answer": "Its eyeball", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9005501dd7bf43be5e866", "question": "How many US gallons is in a barrel of oil?", "answer": "42", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a67d", "question": "Wisconsin has a shoreline along which two Great Lakes?", "answer": "Superior and Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5fa", "question": "The sleeve insignia of a First Class Petty Officer in the US Navy is a spread eagle over how many chevrons?", "answer": "Three", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e93a594d6f11f394a3b2d53", "question": "What sport was Arthur Ashe associated with?", "answer": "Tennis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a65a", "question": "What is the capital of Montana?", "answer": "Helena", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396e1", "question": "What TV show takes place in Pawnee, Indiana?", "answer": "Parks and Recreation", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4c9", "question": "What year marked the first appearance of Pinocchio?", "answer": "1883", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe69fc820565ad31a57c790", "question": "Where did the \u201cwiki\u201d in Wikipedia come from?", "answer": "Hawaiian for \"fast\" or \"quick\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bea6", "question": "What hobby uses the Yoshizawa-Randlett diagramming system?", "answer": "Origami", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdab4fa0b8cce1e6fda7049", "question": "What English word has the most definitions/meanings?", "answer": "Run", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c89dca011619dd6d415489", "question": "Whose mom in South Park was sucked into a toilet?", "answer": "Clyde\u2019s", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4cc", "question": "What US state capital took its name from the French for \"red stick\"?", "answer": "Baton Rouge", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2ed", "question": "Where is the most dangerous type of thunderstorms?", "answer": "Supercells", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133920b", "question": "What early 1990's dance craze was launched by \"The Simpsons\"?", "answer": "The Bartman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594a61ca2ebb971c1417fb8a", "question": "By what name is \"One Thousand and One Nights\" better known as in the English language?", "answer": "Arabian Nights", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c69", "question": "What literary character, in a novel by Cervantes, had a sidekick named Sancho Panza?", "answer": "Don Quixote", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59e8029ede59ea584496fe97", "question": "The song \"Hand on Your Heart\" was a hit in 1989 for which singer?", "answer": "Kylie Minogue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aec5", "question": "Which Saint was murdered at Canterbury Cathedral in 1170?", "answer": "Thomas Beckett", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8c1", "question": "Coq au vin is a dish made with which type of meat?", "answer": "Chicken", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae5c", "question": "During what decade did the twist become the big dance craze?", "answer": "1960s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59524044736d4be723796b60", "question": "What island is the most populous in Canada?", "answer": "Island of Montreal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd2d6af2596a59cbdfbd3ad", "question": "Which company released the first e-reader device?", "answer": "Barnes and Noble", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d10", "question": "What movie's first sequel featured the subtitle \"On the Rocks\"?", "answer": "Arthur", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60121cc563c99d48cd169b18", "question": "What is the real name of Chicago\u2019s \"The Bean\"?", "answer": "\"Cloud Gate\", by artist Sir Anish Kapoor, gives a perfect view of the Chicago skyline in its reflective stainless steel surface.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c157", "question": "Which three ingredients does a Kamikaze cocktail contain?", "answer": "Vodka, triple sec and lime juice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba21", "question": "What is the name given to the Cricketer's Year book, where all cricketing laws and scores are reported?", "answer": "Wisdens Almanac", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a717", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Wolverine State\"?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339338", "question": "What US state is Sheldon from the TV show \"The Big Bang Theory\" from?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeb1", "question": "Over what part of Captain Robert Jenkins were Britain and Spain at war in 1739?", "answer": "His ear", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecc727ec223966ae8f888b", "question": "What is the name of the device used to facilitate dream sharing in the movie \"Inception\"?", "answer": "A Portable Automated Somnacin IntraVenous Device (PASIV)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396ab", "question": "In what film did real life siblings Jake and Maggie Gyllenhaal play brother and sister onscreen?", "answer": "Donnie Darko", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60062a94c9d816e292245c1a", "question": "Coosje van Bruggen and Claes Oldenburg first collaborated on what sculpture?", "answer": "The husband/wife team, first collaborated on\u00a0\"Flashlight\"\u00a0(1981), a huge outdoor sculpture at the University of Nevada, Las Vegas.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133945f", "question": "How does Jack die in the movie \"The Shining\"?", "answer": "He freezes to death", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a665", "question": "Pamlico Sound is located along the shores of which state?", "answer": "North Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b358dd55db0d66a186cb564", "question": "Where would you most often come across a chicane?", "answer": "On a motor racing track", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338da0", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Jones?", "answer": "Henry Fielding", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf2c", "question": "How many balls are on a pool table at the start of a game?", "answer": "16", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5af259acb63e5727cf5a4851", "question": "Which rock band released the singles \"Karma Police\" and \"Creep\"?", "answer": "Radiohead", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a5530b3e1c6f9840ba31a0", "question": "Which band recorded the album \"Fly Like an Eagle\" in 1975 to 1976?", "answer": "Steve Miller Band", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391d9", "question": "What was the official name of the first Indiana Jones movies?", "answer": "Raiders of the Lost Ark", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcba", "question": "What model was married to musician Seal?", "answer": "Heidi Klum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af8a", "question": "What did the 13th Constitutional Amendment ban?", "answer": "Slavery", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ded0acea2747c8aff16d2b", "question": "Tin is primarily obtained from which ore?", "answer": "Cassiterite", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58b8cd1794b094db915830a4", "question": "How many Academy Award nominations did Leonardo DiCaprio receive before finally winning the award for Best Actor in 2016?", "answer": "6", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe733d3eec85e375820b225", "question": "What meeting of world powers near the end of World War II is often said to mark the beginning of the Cold War?", "answer": "The Yalta Conference", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8d6", "question": "In what country would you find the mouths of the river Rhine?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e20", "question": "\"Songbird\" is a book about what jazz singer's remarkable posthumous career?", "answer": "Eva Cassidy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6eb", "question": "What does an archer keep his arrows in?", "answer": "Quiver", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a3a", "question": "Whose novel \"Sweet Thursday\" formed the basis for the 1955 Rodgers & Hammerstein musical \"Pipe Dream\"?", "answer": "John Steinbeck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab2d", "question": "Suva is the capital of which Melanesian country?", "answer": "Fiji", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c9af877e98cb977789fa", "question": "In which city will you find the Tiergarten Park?", "answer": "Berlin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b35f", "question": "Who was Tommy Lee Jones' upperclassman roommate at Harvard?", "answer": "Al Gore", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59523dc2736d4be723796b47", "question": "What year did the last Province or Territory join Canada?", "answer": "1999", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390a3", "question": "Who is the Roman equivalent of the Greek goddess Demeter?", "answer": "Ceres", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b785", "question": "The person who invented machine-spun cotton candy was what kind of a doctor?", "answer": "A dentist", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339206", "question": "What is Prince's surname?", "answer": "Nelson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac01", "question": "The Plains of Abraham is in which Canadian province?", "answer": "Quebec", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133933f", "question": "In what year did the TV show \"Grey's Anatomy\" premier?", "answer": "2005", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcb4", "question": "What kind of fruit juice is used to mix a Polish Martini?", "answer": "Apple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b931", "question": "What's the traditional dish served at Wimbledon?", "answer": "Strawberries and cream", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ad9de5ee748bb36357acde5", "question": "Who played Matlock in the muder mystery series of the same name?", "answer": "Andy Griffith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ef5", "question": "Which literary work's title character is named Chingachgook?", "answer": "The Last of the Mohicans", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bd8", "question": "What popular actor produced the show \"Entourage\"?", "answer": "Mark Wahlberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b1", "question": "Who played the female lead role in the 2007 movie \"Stardust\"?", "answer": "Claire Danes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bfe0045b668d7dfe168b5c0", "question": "Which desert is located in the southeastern part of California?", "answer": "The Mojave desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399fe", "question": "How many episodes of \"The X-Files\" were made?", "answer": "202", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bcc", "question": "What is the name of Boy George's 1982 debut album?", "answer": "Kissing to be Clever", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393bb", "question": "What was Robert De Niro's nickname in the movie \"Casino\"?", "answer": "Ace", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b636", "question": "Which salad dressing was named after a play?", "answer": "Green Goddess", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59636b66967692ea851899a4", "question": "Which country, that ceased to be a US territory in 1946, celebrates July 4 as its \"Republic Day\"?", "answer": "The Philippines", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac48", "question": "What was the series of campaigns to wrest the Holy Land from Muslim Turks called?", "answer": "The Crusades", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133961f", "question": "What actor played Bill the Butcher in the 2002 movie \"Gangs of New York\"?", "answer": "Daniel Day Lewis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394ee", "question": "What actress fell for an American reporter in the 1953 movie \"Roman Holiday\"?", "answer": "Audrey Hepburn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be2a", "question": "What familiar product is Rich Uncle Pennybags the mascot for?", "answer": "Monopoly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4d9b3908b8581f80b092c3", "question": "What three gaming consoles did Nintendo release in 2017?", "answer": "Nintendo Switch, New Nintendo 2DS XL, and Super NES Classic Edition", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b370a31c3f17ccc40c8e16", "question": "Pubs are said to have evolved from what Anglo-Saxon establishment that started to appear in the 5th century?", "answer": "Alehouses", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd6a1b46c0f9723ab15cb3d", "question": "Who was the first pope to visit the White House?", "answer": "Pope John Paul II", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e5", "question": "What is known as a \"Magnum Opus\"?", "answer": "The greatest, most popular or most renowned achievement of a writer, artist or composer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a18f", "question": "What was the name of Barney and Betty Rubble\u2019s adopted son in \"The Flintstones\"?", "answer": "Bamm-Bamm Rubble", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe1f461145fb2946670739e", "question": "What is the steaming, bubbling bowl that a witch brews spells in?", "answer": "Cauldron", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338de9", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"wok\"?", "answer": "Cantonese", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff214f631a458464a93c45a", "question": "What is the name of the US President's official guest house?", "answer": "Blair House", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9f702ff048f679a45aae2", "question": "What kind of scientist was Luther Burbank?", "answer": "Botanist", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60078b710eee65b76b9f2668", "question": "What name was given to Britain\u2019s policy of avoiding strict enforcement of parliamentary laws on early American colonies?", "answer": "Salutary neglect", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b305", "question": "How did Ponce de Leon, Claudius, and Tycho Brahe all die?", "answer": "They were poisoned", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a728cc86bcd28c11938328c", "question": "Dover is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Delaware", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a173", "question": "Who created the characters Wallace and Gromit?", "answer": "Nick Park", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1a4", "question": "What were Wilma Flintstone and Betty Rubble's maiden names?", "answer": "Slaghoople and McBricker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067d13ff9c0647b50a8072", "question": "Which film was the highest-grossing film of 2016?", "answer": "Captain America: Civil War", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab969186faa38a764be520", "question": "What company did Mercedes-Benz partner with to develop the Smart car?", "answer": "Swatch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be2d", "question": "In what country did Red Bull originate as Krating Daeng?", "answer": "Thailand", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a2", "question": "Who is known as Eminem?", "answer": "Marshall Mathers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a67120565ad31a57c7d9", "question": "What is the name of the first nuclear-powered merchant ship?", "answer": "NS Savannah", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ee2", "question": "What position was first held by Muhammad Naguib?", "answer": "President of Egypt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bab0", "question": "What was the first flavor of Life Savers candy?", "answer": "Peppermint", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f16919f7c52aae91cc07cd", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"The Moonstone\"?", "answer": "Wilkie Collins", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aad", "question": "For whom did Robert May write the story of Rudolph the Red-nosed Reindeer?", "answer": "His daughter, Barbara", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1e6", "question": "What is the official name of the Michelin Man?", "answer": "Bibendum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf4f", "question": "What fish is known as poor mans lobster?", "answer": "Monk Fish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d6a", "question": "What prospector is cremated in poet Robert Service's most famous ballad?", "answer": "Sam McGee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad9dac7e748bb36357acdd5", "question": "What is the largest fish living today?", "answer": "The Whale shark", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4b8", "question": "What South American animal is the world's largest rodent?", "answer": "The capybara", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7cff6877e98cb97778a58", "question": "What modern city is situated near Mount Vesuvius?", "answer": "Naples", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c033", "question": "What is the more common name for serigraphy?", "answer": "Screen printing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe76840eec85e375820b29e", "question": "Which U.S. city is referred to as \"The Hub of the Universe\"?", "answer": "Boston, Massachusetts", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9fd", "question": "What is the capital of Samoa?", "answer": "Apia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c10", "question": "According to Exodus, what is the eighth plague of Egypt?", "answer": "Locusts", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339873", "question": "In Disney's \"Alice in Wonderland\", who is the companion of The Walrus?", "answer": "A Carpenter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "591c37f6815febcc896f9277", "question": "What is the sixth sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Virgo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe0003b1cf6db9ac4808d0f", "question": "What is the tallest building in South America?", "answer": "Gran Torre Santiago, Santiago, Chile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d00", "question": "What letter accounts for one of every eight used in written English?", "answer": "E", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b13ce662d71a53650fcf", "question": "What is the name of the train station that services Hogwarts School?", "answer": "Hogsmeade Station", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf32", "question": "In Norway what is a Brisling?", "answer": "A Sprat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6012189c63c99d48cd169af6", "question": "Where were the fortune cookies invented?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a0c", "question": "What is the name of the gypsy girl who Quasimodo fell in love with?", "answer": "Esmeralda", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adef", "question": "What year did the English Civil War start?", "answer": "1642", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5be57d5e5415ba52ed6f0aa6", "question": "How many minutes are in a day?", "answer": "1,440", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8d6", "question": "Someone who is polytheistic believes in more than one what?", "answer": "God", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0e0", "question": "During which war did the flag flying above Fort McHenry inspire Francis Scott Key's \"The Star-Spangled Banner\"?", "answer": "War of 1812", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fde5189c6c6b019850c9a8f", "question": "What was the very first ship sunk in action in World War II?", "answer": "SS Athenia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58c8a89890aac110e4167090", "question": "The Somersby cider brand is owned by which multinational brewing company?", "answer": "Carlsberg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9088901dd7bf43be5e885", "question": "What color is on the outside arc of a rainbow?", "answer": "Red", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd66c4ea5bfecdd737e0892", "question": "Cynophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Dogs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae72", "question": "What berries did pregnant women of the Middle Ages avoid for fear their children would be born with birthmarks?", "answer": "Strawberries", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c745", "question": "In what organ of the human body is the hippocampus?", "answer": "The brain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6017401144491cbd7c5a17b9", "question": "What was the name of the ship that brought news of the Battle of Trafalgar to Britain?", "answer": "HMS Pickle", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a8", "question": "What song is most famous for its suggestive chorus of \"Voulez-vous coucher avec moi (ce soir)\"?", "answer": "Lady Marmalade", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592201b0a4edfd43a087addb", "question": "What is the first name of the fictional character \"Miss Marple\"?", "answer": "Jane", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff14051b0ee8c595b6d399a", "question": "Who was the first African-American Pulitzer Prize winner?", "answer": "Gwendolyn Brooks", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "590678c2ff9c0647b50a804c", "question": "The year 2016 was the 2016th year of what Civil calendar?", "answer": "Gregorian calendar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339498", "question": "What are the names of the Monkees from the TV show of the same name?", "answer": "Mickey, Davey, Peter, Michael", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a2c", "question": "Jenny McCarthy and Carmen Electra were both hosts on what MTV game show during the 1990's?", "answer": "Singled Out", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393ed", "question": "What is the name of the funeral home in the TV show \"Six Feet Under\"?", "answer": "Fisher & Sons", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937ecc208d98002fdd633c0", "question": "Which US state's way of life and culture is described as Cajun?", "answer": "Louisiana's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3be", "question": "What is the most abundant metal in Earth's crust?", "answer": "Aluminium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d66", "question": "Who played the role of TV's D. J. Tanner?", "answer": "Candace Cameron", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60078b640eee65b76b9f2667", "question": "Which seven U.S. states seceded and formed the original Confederacy during the U.S. Civil War?", "answer": "Alabama, Florida, Georgia, Louisiana, Mississippi, South Carolina and Texas.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8b3", "question": "In what city would you find Charles River Esplanade?", "answer": "Boston", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592eae17f83302ff91e46483", "question": "Which creature was the Egyptian God Horus identified with?", "answer": "Falcon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada4", "question": "In what US state was the outlaw Jesse James born?", "answer": "Missouri", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a23e", "question": "Which studio album did Elton John release in 1971?", "answer": "Madman Across the Water", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5901d8c7709c1c34536e6ea7", "question": "In what country was the first coin operated slot machine invented?", "answer": "US", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc55", "question": "Who was the first woman to head the International Montary Fund?", "answer": "Christine Lagarde", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2a5", "question": "What nation was led by Peter the Great?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3a9", "question": "What US city is nicknamed \"The Big Peach\"?", "answer": "Atlanta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5909d339bb53d1af65886510", "question": "On what date did the TV special \"A Charlie Brown Christmas\" made its debut on CBS?", "answer": "December 9, 1965", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58dba497874c93a3298b2146", "question": "What is believed to have eventually killed Oliver Cromwell?", "answer": "Malaria and urinary/kidney infection", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5bd05bbb40191c55fd523fb3", "question": "What is the most known horror video game involving ink?", "answer": "Bendy and the Ink Machine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b671", "question": "Someone who is called a \"flash in the pan\" could also be described as what?", "answer": "A one-hit wonder", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9eb", "question": "On which river is Warsaw to be found?", "answer": "Vistula", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a971", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The House of Lords?", "answer": "The United Kingdom", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef61876ce05a3942286e53", "question": "Which Hall of Fame British rocker is also an astrophysicist?", "answer": "Brian May", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f0a9ff048f679a45aaa2", "question": "Selenophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "The Moon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338919", "question": "Who runs the orphanage in the musical \"Annie\"?", "answer": "Miss Hannigan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b084", "question": "What object did Ben Franklin attach to the end of a kite string to prove that lightning is electricity?", "answer": "A metal key", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd66246a5bfecdd737e0843", "question": "Who was the oldest Chief Justice appointed to the U.S. Supreme Court?", "answer": "Harlan Stone", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4c0e49076251badbeacc", "question": "Who got married in the very first White House wedding?", "answer": "Dolley Madison\u2019s sister -- Lucy Payne Washington, the sister of First Lady Dolley Madison, married Thomas Todd in 1819.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca5b", "question": "What is a sternocleidomastoid?", "answer": "A muscle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133996b", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what was the name of Comic Book Guy's dead dog?", "answer": "Chewbacca", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e4d", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"Steel\"?", "answer": "Shaquille O'Neal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c448", "question": "How many chromosomes does a wolf have?", "answer": "78", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b0", "question": "Simon & Simon, from the TV show by the same name, were in what business?", "answer": "Private Detectives", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7bd0c877e98cb97778952", "question": "What river runs through Baghdad?", "answer": "Tigris", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ab9", "question": "What was the first name of Sherlock Holmes' assistant Dr. Watson?", "answer": "John", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea3856ff048f679a45ab23", "question": "Who is considered the \"father\" of organic chemistry?", "answer": "Friedrich W\u00f6hler", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd81d44d0de9af39e9d468d", "question": "What was the original name for Africa?", "answer": "Alkebulan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f5666033a95c66dc4fe762", "question": "What is the capital of Michigan?", "answer": "Lansing", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a85f", "question": "What are the official languages of Belgium?", "answer": "Dutch, French and German", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fde4eb3c6c6b019850c9a86", "question": "What was eBay.com originally called?", "answer": "AuctionWeb", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c39c", "question": "What constellation is represented by the whale?", "answer": "Cetus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b02", "question": "The ending vocal riff of what 1966 Frank Sinatra song inspired the name of cartoon character dog Scooby-Doo?", "answer": "Strangers in the Night", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b513", "question": "What is mixed with Kahlua or Tia Maria to make a Black Russian?", "answer": "Vodka", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aee6", "question": "Who preceded Georges Pompidou as French President?", "answer": "Charles de Gaulle", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a192", "question": "In what 1985 movie did Ally Sheedy play the role of Allison Reynolds?", "answer": "The Breakfast Club", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b1f", "question": "What place did Dante describe as having \"Abandon hope, all ye who enter here\" written over its doors?", "answer": "Hell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9a1", "question": "What does the abbreviation NATO stand for?", "answer": "North Atlantic Treaty Organization", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fede5de6ce05a3942286df2", "question": "What stop-motion animated film by Tim Burton stars Johnny Depp and Helena Bonham Carter?", "answer": "\"Corpse Bride\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9f2", "question": "What year was the operating system \"Windows\" first released to the market?", "answer": "1985", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef5ee66ce05a3942286e3b", "question": "Kyle Korver is frequently mistaken for which famous actor?", "answer": "Ashton Kutcher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c743", "question": "What is the more common term for amblyopia?", "answer": "Lazy eye", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c3c", "question": "Who wrote the play \"Long Day's Journey Into Night\"?", "answer": "Eugene O'Neill", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea388bff048f679a45ab24", "question": "What scientist proposed the theory of continental drift?", "answer": "Alfred Wegener", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea32aeff048f679a45aae9", "question": "How often do your taste buds regenerate on average?", "answer": "Every ten days", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b27", "question": "What 1991 River Phoenix/Keanu Reeves film took its title from lyrics in a B-52's song?", "answer": "My Own Private Idaho", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6002447a4be4723ccac221a4", "question": "How long did it take Leonardo da Vinci to paint the Mona Lisa's smile?", "answer": "Leonardo's greatest triumph was the smile of the Mona Lisa, which he labored on for 16 years up until his death.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339666", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Springfield's newspaper?", "answer": "The Springfield Shopper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd82178d0de9af39e9d46a6", "question": "What is the largest contiguous land empire in history?", "answer": "Mongol", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e0b", "question": "The Don McLean song that begins \"Starry starry night\" is actually named for what painter?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a1e1d9cb5a031299b74573c", "question": "What century did the Europeans dicover the Okapi?", "answer": "20th Century", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339252", "question": "What city is the setting for the movie \"Gladiator\"?", "answer": "Rome", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa40d5c73aa70ea0b70b0a", "question": "Where is the first underwater art museum in the U.S.?", "answer": "Santa Rosa Beach, Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa24", "question": "In which US state is Cornell University?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7b3", "question": "The Linke Scale is used to measure the blueness of what?", "answer": "The sky", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c088", "question": "What is Plutophobia the fear of?", "answer": "Wealth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be8e", "question": "What is the American term for the rope maneuver called \"abseiling\" in Europe?", "answer": "Rappeling", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339361", "question": "What occupation did Mary Richards have on \"The Mary Tyler Moore Show\"?", "answer": "Assistant producer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f40", "question": "Drug lord Mr. Big is the villain of what James Bond movie?", "answer": "Live and Let Die", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c77cf8024f0f7a362efd54e", "question": "In \"The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time\", what are the names of the six races?", "answer": "Hylian, Kokiri, Goron, Zora, Gerudo, Shiekah.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339675", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what color is the tablecloth in the Simpsons' kitchen?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec845aec223966ae8f87fe", "question": "Which Mario character has appeared in all but one \"Mario Party\" game?", "answer": "Wario", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bbd529500d154d7af00b8da", "question": "Jarvis Cocker was the frontman of which British band?", "answer": "Pulp", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcaa", "question": "What whiskey cocktail lands its name to the short glass also called a \"lowball\"?", "answer": "The old-fashioned", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa8ce6ce05a3942286ed7", "question": "Who played the part of Max Cady in the 1991 thriller \"Cape Fear\"?", "answer": "Robert De Niro", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1b6", "question": "Which US state was boxer John L. Sullivan born in?", "answer": "Massachusetts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59cdb12065ff7d326b622a66", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Curium?", "answer": "Cm", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a64", "question": "What spirit is the comic book nemesis of Casper, the Friendly Ghost?", "answer": "Spooky", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5c3e9b06ebfabb9c85d8a981", "question": "\"Four legs good, two legs bad\" is a quotation from which novel?", "answer": "Animal Farm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4b6649076251badbeac4", "question": "Maya Angelou spoke at the inauguration of which U.S. President?", "answer": "Maya Angelou recited her poem \"On the Pulse of Morning,\" at President Bill Clinton's first inauguration in 1993.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be32", "question": "How many players are there in a standard ice hockey team?", "answer": "Six", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa5fb6ce05a3942286ec8", "question": "Who directed the film \"Home Alone?\"", "answer": "Chris Columbus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7e910b24f84e0b9f9ffc8", "question": "What year did Botswana gain its independence from the United Kingdom?", "answer": "1966", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a123", "question": "What are the escape tunnels in the film \"The Great Escape\" called?", "answer": "Tom, Dick and Harry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b042", "question": "What English king was known as the \"Lionheart\"?", "answer": "Richard (I)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133925f", "question": "What band turned down an offer from \"Gap\" to use their song \"Don't Panic\"?", "answer": "Coldplay", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339880", "question": "In Star Wars, what disguise did Luke and Han wear on the Death Star?", "answer": "Stormtrooper armor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339142", "question": "What year was the opera \"Death in Venice\" first performed?", "answer": "1973", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58c8a7c490aac110e4167089", "question": "What important property do cider apples have that most eating and cooking apples don\u2019t?", "answer": "High sugar content", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c158", "question": "Who was the first thoroughbred horse to win one million dollars?", "answer": "Citation", "category": "general"}]